Guide to the E. Clowes Chorley Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
E. Clowes Chorley papers
1765-1949
MS 132
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
2.5
Research materials for a history of the Protestant Episcopal Church, drafts of articles written for the Historical Magazine of the Protestant Episcopal Church and other publications, and for several books on church history. Also included is an extensive autograph collection of over 300 letters of Protestant Episcopal bishops.Of particular interest in the research materials are correspondence and documents of Bishop Alfred Lee and others relating to missionary work in Mexico between 1875-1915. Also in the papers is a collection of sermons (1765-1931), a scrapbook compiled by Chorley about the general convention of 1913, and a brief diary for the year of 1932.
Chorley, E. Clowes (Edward Clowes), 1865-1949
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of E. Clowes Chorley, 1937-1946.
Scope and Contents
2.5' (6 boxes, 1 folio) Dates: 1765-1949, n.d.
The history of the Protestant Episcopal Church in America is the subject of the E. Clowes Chorley Papers. Chorley was a historiographer of the Protestant Episcopal Church, and the founder and first editor in 1932 of the Historical Magazine of the Protestant Episcopal Church. A sizeable portion of his papers consists of research materials and drafts of articles written for the Magazine and other publications, and for several books on church history. Autographs and writings of Protestant Episcopal bishops and others important in the history of the church, which Chorley collected, make up the remainder of his papers.
The E. Clowes Chorley Papers have been divided into three series: AUTOGRAPH COLLECTION, RESEARCH PAPERS, and WRITINGS. In the first series are over 300 letters and autographs of Protestant Episcopal bishops and others, arranged alphabetically. Series II contains original documents and other materials of various types. These include documents and correspondence of Bishop Alfred Lee and others relating to missionary work and related activities in Mexico between 1875 and 1915; a small collection of sermons, both manuscripts and typescripts, ranging from 1765 to 1931 and arranged alphabetically by author; books, articles, addresses, and similar writings by and about Protestant Episcopal bishops and church history; and a miscellany of documents, minutes, and so forth from Protestant Episcopal churches, as well as a scrapbook compiled by Chorley about the general convention of 1913. Series III contains drafts of books, articles, and addresses by Chorley, his notes on church history, and a diary for the year 1932 enclosing newspaper clippings and other items. It has only scattered entries.
Reverend Chorley donated these papers to Yale University in a series of gifts between 1937 and 1946. Materials related to these papers may be found in the Elisha Lord Cleaveland Papers (Manuscript Group Number 139) and the Protestant Episcopal Bishops Collection (Manuscript Group Number 21).
Missionaries -- Mexico; Mexico -- Religious life; Autographs; Scrapbooks; Sermons; Clergy; Acheson, Edward Campion, 1858-1934; Bedell, Gregory Thurston, 1817-1892; Brewster, Benjamin, 1860-1941; Brewster, Chauncey B. (Chauncey Bunce), 1848-1941; Brooks, Phillips, 1835-1893; Burgess, Frederick, bp., 1853-; Chase, Carlton, 1794-1870; Chorley, E. Clowes (Edward Clowes), 1865-1949; Doane, William Croswell, 1832-1913; Eastburn, Manton, 1801-1872; Gailor, Thomas Frank, 1856-1935; Garland, Thomas James, bp., 1866-1931; Hare, William Hobart, 1838-1909; Hopkins, John Henry, 1792-1868; Howe, Mark Anthony DeWolfe, bp., 1808-1895; Hulse, Hiram Richard, 1868-1938; Huntington, F. D. (Frederic Dan), 1819-1904; Kemper, Jackson, 1789-1870; Kerfoot, John Barrett, bp., 1816-1881; Kilgour, Robert, 1714-1790; Lee, Alfred, 1807-1887; Lines, Edwin Stevens, bp., 1845-; Manning, William Thomas, Bp., 1866-1949; Muhlenberg, William Augustus, 1796-1877; Nelson, Richard Henry, bp., 1859-1931; Onderdonk, Benjamin Tredwell, bp., 1791-1861; Potter, Henry Codman, 1834-1908; Potter, Horatio, 1802-1887; Seymour, George F. (George Franklin), 1829-1906; Shipman, Herbert, bp., 1869-1930; Skinner, John, bp. of Aberdeen, 1744-1816; Slattery, Charles Lewis, 1867-1930; Tuttle, Daniel Sylvester, 1837-1923; Whipple, Henry Benjamin, 1822-1901; Whittingham, William Rollinson, 1805-1879; Williams, J. (John), 1817-1899; Episcopal Church
- Autograph Collection, Series I
  - Autograph letters
    - Acheson, Edward Campion, 1858-1934, 1921 April 27, 1932 October 24, 27, December 9 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Adams, William Forbes, 1833-1920, 1894 January 19 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Addison, Daniel Dulany, 1863-1936, 1912 December 28, 1924 February 19 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Anderson, Charles Palmerston, 1863-1930, 1910 December 9 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Armitage, William Edmond, 1830-1873, 1869 January 29 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Atkinson, Thomas, 1807-1881, 1853 January 24, 1868 December 22 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Atwill, Edward Robert, 1840-1911, 1894 January 16 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Atwood, Julius Walter, 1857-, 1914 April 3, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Auer, John Gottlieb, 1832-1874, 1873 August 6, 1874 February 13 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Aves, Henry Damerel, 1853-1936, 1921 January 25 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Babcock, Samuel Gavitt, 1851-, 1916 November 27 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Balch, Lewis P. W., 1857 September 28 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Beal, Harry, 1885-, 1935 May 18 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Beardsley, Eben Edwards, 1808-1891, 1866 February 13 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Beatty, Troy, 1866-1922, 1921 April 26 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Beckwith, Charles Minnigerode, 1851-1928, 1916 October 16 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Beckwith, John Watrus, 1831-1890, 1869 January 1, 1883 December 3 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Bedell, Gregory Thurston, 1817-1892, 1876 March 4, 1878 December 17, 1879 February 23, 1881 September 2 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Beecher, George Allen, 1868-, 1916 October 21 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Bennett, Granville Gaylord, 1882-, 1922 April 26 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Biller, George, Jr., 1874-1915, 1915 April 23 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Bissell, William Henry Augustus, 1814-1893, 1869 June 28 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Bliss, George Yemens, 1864-1924, 1915 April 14, 1916 November 3 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Boone, William Jones, 1811-1864, 1859 July 4 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Booth, Samuel B., 1927 May 17 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Bratton, Theodore Du Bose, 1862-, 1914 April 23, 1923 November 9 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Brent, Charles Henry, 1862-, 1894 January 15, 1925 November 19 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Brewer, Leigh Richmond, 1839-1916, 1887 February 26 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Brewster, Benjamin, 1860-, 1913 February 14, 1915 April 21 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Brewster, Chauncey, 1848- 1941, 1912 March 2, 1915 April 30 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Brooke, Francis Key, 1852-1918, 1899 October 10 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Brooks, Phillips, 1835-1893, 1862 June 23, 1883 September 28, 1888 December 24, 1889 February 4 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Brown, John, 1853 June 24 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Brown, William Cabell, 1861-1927, 1915 April 13, 1923 October 30 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Brown, William Montgomery, 1855-, 1925 September 5 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Brownell, Thomas Church, 1779-1865, 1824 August 15 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Budlong, Frederick Grandy, 1881-, 1931 November 17 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Burch, Charles Sumner, 1855-1920, 1916 June 2 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Burgess, Alexander, 1819-1901, 1887 January 27 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Burgess, Frederick, 1853-1925, 1901 November 25, 1905 July 14, 1906 April 20, June 9, 1915 April 12 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Burgess, George, 1809-1866, 1852 February 10, 1860 August 8 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Burleson, Hugh Latimer, 1865-1933, 1928 February 28, 1930 April 10 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Burrows, George Sherman, -1937, 1937 July 2 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Burton, Lewis William, 1852-, 1919 April 15, 1921 May 1 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Capers, William Theodotus, 1867-, 1917 January 2 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Campbell, Robert E., 1933 March 31 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Carnegie, W_____ H., 1932 March 4 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Chase, Carlton, 1794-1870, 1842 July 29, 1854 August 17, 1864 August 28, 1866 March 24 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Cheshire, Joseph Blount, 1850-1932, 1916, 1931 February 6 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Clark, Thomas March, 1812-1903, 1894 January 15 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Clarkson, Robert Harper, 1826-1884, 1883 March 13 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Clingman, Charles, 1883-, 1935 February 25 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Cobbs, Nicholas Hammer, 1796-1861, 1860 March 13 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Codman, Robert, 1859-1915, 1901 June 22 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Coleman, Leighton, 1837-1907, 1903 October 12 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Colmore, Charles Blayney, 1879-, 1916 October 27 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Cook, Philip, 1875-, 1923 November 2 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Courtney, Frederick, 1837-1919, 1883 September 28, 1914 October 17 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Coxe, Arthur Cleveland, 1818-1896, 1866 September 10, 1896 [June 29] (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Creighton, Frank W., 1927 January 13 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Cross, Edward Makin, 1880-, 1923 November 20 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Croswell, Harry, 1778-1858, 1856 September 27 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Croswell, William, 1804-1851, 1843 June 20 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Cummins, George David, 1822-1876, 1845 June 28 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Davenport, George William, 1870-, 1925 April 4 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Deane, Frederic Llewelyn, bp. of Aberdeen and Orkney, 1875-, 1934 December 2, 1938 January 7 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - de Cartier de Marchienne, Emile, baron, 1871-, 1922 May 19 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Doane, George Washington, 1799-1859, [1838?] June 15 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Doane, William Croswell, 1832-1913, 1877 August 30, 1879 February 25, 1885 June 24, 1895 November 19 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Ducachet, H_____ W., 1847 November 12 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Dudley, Thomas Underwood, 1837-1904, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Eastburn, Manton, 1801-1872, 1854 March 28, June 1, 1855 April 6, 1856 February 18, 1859 April 27, 1862 February 17, 1865 October 19 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Edsall, Samuel Cook, 1860-1917, 1899 September 13 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Elliott, Robert Woodward, 1840-1887, 1878 November 7, 1883 May 28 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Elliott, Stephen, 1806-1866, 1854 June 3, 1857 August 10 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Faber, William Frederic, 1850-1934, 1915 April 15, 1921 April 28 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Fairbanks, George Rainsford, 1820, 1896 October 19 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Fawcett, Edward, 1865-1935, 1920 November 13 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Ferguson,_____ D., 1893 May 18 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Ferris, David Lincoln, 1864-, 1928 October 15 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Fiske, Charles, 1868-, [1922], 1940 July 2, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Fosbroke, Hughell Edgar Woodall, 1875-, 1934 November 8 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Fox, Herbert Henry Heywood, 1871-, 1928 June 30 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Francis, Joseph Marshall, 1862, 1899 October 3, 1915 May 5 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Freeman, James E., 1927 May 23 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Funsten, James Bowen, 1856-1918, 1918 February 24 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Gadsden, Christopher Edwards, 1785-1852, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Gailor, Thomas Frank, 1856-1935, 1916 April 30, 1921 April 6, Oct, 1923 January 23, 1932 June 7 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Galleher, John Nicholas, 1839-1891, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Gardiner, Theophilus Momolu, 1870-, 1928 October 1 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Garland, Thomas James, 1866-1931, 1915 April 14, 1916 October 27, 1921 April 25 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Garrett, Alexander Charles, 1832-1924, 1886 November 23 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Gibson, Robert Atkinson, 1846-1919, 1899 August 4 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Gilbert, Charles Kendall, 1878-, 1930 June 27, 1931 February 6, 1934 October 30 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Gilbert, Mahlon Norris, 1848-1900, [1899] July 26 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Gillespie, George DeNormandie, 1819-1909, 1881 September 27, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Gilman, Alfred Alonzo, 1878-, 1923 June 26 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Glyn, Edward Carr, bp. of Peterborough, 1843-, 1915 April 20 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Goodwin, Daniel, 1835-1922, 1917 September 13 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Grafton, Charles Chapman, 1832-1912, [1894 February 19], [1899] December 24 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Gravatt, William Loyall, 1858, 1916 October 27 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Graves, Anson Rogers, 1842-1931, 1898 November 8 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Graves, Frederick Rogers, 1858, 1907 December 16, 1921 March 21 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Gray, William Crane, 1835-1919, 1915 April 16 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Green, William Mercer, 1798-1887, 1869 January 4, 1882 January 11 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Green, William Mercer, 1876-, 1919 September 8 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Gregg, Alexander, 1819-1893, 1866 October 27, 1875 March 10 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Greer, David Hummell, 1844-1919, 1888 December 12, 1904 January 30 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Grierson, Charles Thornton Primrose, bp. of Down and Connor and Dromore, 1857-, 1934 May 25 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Griswold, Sheldon Munson, 1861-1930, undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Guerry, William Alexander, 1861-1928, 1915 April 16 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Guthrie, William Norman, 1868, 1932 June 13 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Hale, Charles Reuben, 1837-1900, 1879 February 24, 1885 June 5, July 21, 1895 November 5 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Hall, Arthur Crawshay Alliston, 1894 March 3, 1915 April 26 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Harding, Alfred, 1852-1923, 1918 October 12 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Hare, William Hobart, 1838-1909, [1872?], 1883 September 28, [1887] February 9, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Harris, Samuel Smith, 1841-1888, 1880 November 9 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Hart, Samuel, 1845-1917, 1915 March 24 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Hawks, Cicero Stephens, 1812-1868, 1862 October 15 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Helfenstein, Edward Trail, 1865-, 1928 November 18 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Hobart, John Henry, 1775-1830, 1920 May 11 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Hodges, George, 1856-1919, 1915 April 15 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Holly, James Theodore, 1829-1911, 1862 December 2/5 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Hopkins, John Henry, 1792-1868, 1838 June 19, October 9, 27, 1844 May 20, 1866 July 10, August 9 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Horner, Junius Moore, 1859-1933, 1899 July 26 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Howden, Frederick Bingham, 1869-, 1914 April 9, 1915 April 30 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Howe, Mark Anthony DeWolfe, 1808-1895, 1862 December 2, 1874 November 3, 1876 November 24, 1878 April 1, December 10, 1881 October 7 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Howe, William Bell White, 1823-1894, 1875 March 17 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Hulse, Hiram Richard, 1868-, 1915 January 30, April 15, 1918 October 1, November 18, 1920 September 16, 1922 July 31, August 21, 1926 March 26, 1927 January 3 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Hunting, George Coolidge, 1871-1924, 1919 July 7, 1924 February 14 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Huntington, Daniel Trumbull, 1868-, [1919?] (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Huntington, Frederic Dan, 1819-1904, 1872 October 10, December 1, 1873 February 16, 1878 October 17 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Huntington, William Reed, 1838-1909, 1876 October 3, 1883 September 28 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Israel, Rogers, 1854-1921, 1916 October 21 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Ives, Levi Silliman, 1797-1867, 1844 July 10, 22 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Jaggar, Thomas Augustus, 1839-1912, 1898 May 17 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Jett, Robert Carter, 1865-, 1921 April 26 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Johns, Henry Van Dyke, 1803-1859, 1839 September 10 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Johns, John, 1796-1876, 1849 September 20, 1869 January 18 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Johnson, Frederick Foote, 1866-, 1917 August 6 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Johnson, Hewlett, 1874-, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Johnson, Joseph Horsfall, 1847-1928, 1914 April 6 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Jones, Paul, 1880-, 1915 April 15, 1918 March 4 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Keator, Frederic William, 1855-1924, 1915 April 17, [1916] October 16 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Keep, Dustin Baxter, 1909 October 24 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Kemper, Jackson, 1789-1870, 1839 March 27, 1840 March 19, 1843 February 11, 1844 November 28, 1863 October 2 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Kendrick, John Mills, 1836-1911, 1889 October 29 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Kerfoot, John Barrett, 1816-1881, 1843 July 12, 1874 December 9, 1875 April 5, 1876 January 14, February 15, 22, March 11, 24, 25, 27, 30, August 9, 18, 1878 December 6, 12, 17, 19, 1886 November 29 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Kilgour, Robert, 1714-1790, 1775 March 21 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Kinsman, Frederick Joseph, 1868-, 1908 November 6, 1910 April 14 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Kinsolving, George Herbert, 1849-1928, 1915 April 13 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Kinsolving, Lucien L., 1927 May 24 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Kip, William Ingraham, 1811-1893, 1841 December 6, 1884 November 19 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Knickerbacker, David Buel, 1833-1894, 1894 August 7 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Lawrence, William, 1850-1941, 1899 July 25, 1921 May 4 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Lay, Henry Champlin, 1823-1885, 1873 July 22 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Leaming, Jeremiah, 1717-1804, 1784 April 24 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Lee, Alfred, 1807-1887, 1843 October 7, 1862 November 6, December 1 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Lee, Henry Washington, 1815-1874, 1861 February 1 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Leonard, William Andrew, 1848-1930, 1907 November 13, 1915 April 20 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Lines, Edwin Stevens, 1845-1927, 1915 April 22, 1916 November 23, 1923 October 25 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Littlejohn, Abram Newkirk, 1824-1901, 1883 October 23, 1894 April 11 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Lloyd, Arthur Selden, 1857-, 1919 September 12, 1923 February 8 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Longley, Harry Sherman, 1868-, 1916 October 27 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Lyman, Theodore Benedict, 1815-1893, 1841 April 5, 1877 February 26 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - McConnell, Samuel David, 1845-1939, 1883 September 28, 1932 January 13 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - McCormick, John Newton, 1863-, 1910 October 6, 1919 September 4 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - McCoskey, Samuel Allen, 1804-1886, 1869 January 29 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - McDowell, William G., 1932 February 2 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - McElwain, Frank Arthur, 1875-, 1915 April 18, 1919 April 3 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - McIlvaine, Charles Petitt, 1799-1873, 1838 October 24 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - MacKay-Smith, Alexander, 1850-1911, undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - McKim, John, 1852-1936, 1894 September 20 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - McLaren, William Edward, 1835-1905, 1881 October 22 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - McVickar, William Neilson, 1843-1910, 1897 January 3 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Mampoteng, Charles, 1934 February 23 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Mann, Alexander, 1860-, 1924 June 20 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Mann, Cameron, 1851-1932, 1894 February 12 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Manning, William Thomas, 1866-, 1921 February 11, July 19, 1922 October 26, 1923 November 24, 1927 June 23, 1928 August 25, 1930 July 17, [1938] December 22 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Matthews, Paul, 1866-, 1923 November 21 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Meade, William, 1789-1862, 1813 December 31, 1857 March 27 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Mikell, Henry Judah, 1873-, 1919 May 19 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Millspaugh, Frank Rosebrook, 1848-1916, 1916 May 22 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Milnor, James, 1773-1844, 1818 May 7 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Moore, Benjamin, 1748-1816
      General
      See: box 1, folder 19
    - Moore, Harry Tunis, 1874-, 1921 April 26 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Morehouse, Linden H., 1936 November 9 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Moreland, William Hall, 1861-, 1915 April 17 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Morris, Benjamin Wistar, 1819-1906, 1866 October 23 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Morrison, Theodore Nevin, 1850-1929, 1915 April 17 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Mosher, Gouverneur Frank, 1926 July 23 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Moulton, ______, 1926 January 30 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Muhlenberg, William Augustus, 1796-1877, 1822 February 26, 1839 February 18, June 10 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Murray, John G., 1926 July 10, 1927 December 28 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Neely, Henry Adams, 1830-1899, 1879 March 4, 1892 June 27 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Nelson, Cleland Kinloch, 1852-1917, 1895 January 10 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Nelson, Richard Henry, 1859-1931, 1908 February 10, 1913 March 18, 1920 October 9 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Nichols, William Ford, 1849-1924, 1906 August 22, 1915 April 16 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Nicholson, C_____ P. S., 1934 May 28 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Nicholson, Isaac Lea, 1844-1906, 1885 July 20, 1906 June 27 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Niles, William Woodruff, 1832-1914, 1913 May 19 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Odenheimer, William Henry, 1817-1879, 1844 November 16, 1860 September 13 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Oldham, George Ashton, 1877-, 1923 October 11 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Olmsted, Charles Sanford, 1853-1918, 1915 April 11 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Olmsted, Charles Tyler, 1842-1924, 1915 April 13 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Onderdonk, Benjamin Tredwell, 1791-1861, 1833 October 2, 1843 June 15, 1844 April 18, July 6 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Osborne, Edward William, 1845-1926, 1915 April 12 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Overs, Walter Henry, 1870-1934, [post 1925] (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Paddock, Benjamin Henry, 1828-1891, [1887?] April 9 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Paddock, John Adams, 1825-1894, 1881 Oct, 1888 December 17 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Paddock, Robert Lewis, 1869-, 1922 January 19 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Paddock, Wilbur F., 1883 September 28 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Page, Herman, 1866-, 1916 November 1, 1932 December 29 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Paret, William, 1826-1911, 1886 December 24 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Parker, Edward Melville, 1855-1925, 1921 April 28 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Parker, Sarah B. (Mrs. George Stanley), undated (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Parsons, Edward Lambe, 1868-, 1921 March 1, 1930 April 14, 1941 October 30, 1945 July 25 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Partridge, Sidney Catlin, 1857-1930, [1915] April 16 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Payne, John, 1815-1874, 1855 March 11 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Penick, Charles Clifton, 1843-1914, 1908 January 24 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Penick, Edwin Anderson, 1887-, 1922 November 13 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Perkins, Joshua Newton, 1881 November 28, 1913 January 10 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Perry, James De Wolfe, 1871-, 1921 April 29, 1930 April 11, 1931 December 10 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Perry, William Stevens, 1832-1898, 1883 September 28, 1894 February 1 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Peterkin, George William, 1841-1916, 1899 September 20 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Pierce, Henry Niles, 1820-1899, 1891 August 11 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Pinkney, William, 1810-1883, 1883 February 16 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Polk, Leonidas, 1806-1864, 1855 June 18, October 26 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    - Potter, Alonzo, 1800-1865, 1862 October 30, 1863 November 23 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Potter, Henry Codman, 1835-1909, 1869 May 24, 1879 February 22, 1882 January 4, 1885 October 16, 1893 March 8, April 24, 1898 July 5, 1899 October 2-3, 1903 January 30, March 13, 1907 December 13, 1908 February 8 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Potter, Horatio, 1802-1887, 1844 September 18, 1862 October 9, 1879 June 6, 1880 March 31, April 8, 1882 May 12, December 28, 1883 February 2, undated (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Presbury, Willard, 1842 November 30 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    - Quin, Clinton Simon, 1883-, 1924 October 16, 1940 March 20 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Quintard, Charles Todd, 1824-1898, 1868 December 30, 1891 September 1 (Box 2, Folder 27)